BRUCE MCELROY

412-414-4404 • bruce.mcelroy@Gmail.com 1203 Shadycrest Drive • Pittsburgh, PA 15216

BACKGROUND SUMMARY

I am a front end developer by day ... and a front end developer by night. My profession is my passion and way of life. I do not consider what I do a job. I continue working on personal projects after "work" hours. I strive to be challenged and I am very self motivated. I am currently learning Ruby on Rails and have experience in most current frameworks including bootstrap, foundation and the semantic grid system. I feel obligated to stay up-to-date on ALL of the latest design and development trends on the internet to effectively keep my projects fresh and future proof. My goal is to be an asset to your company and wear multiple hats and help streamline projects.

EDUCATION

Pittsburgh Technical Institute, Oakdale, PA | GPA: 3.90 Associate in Science Degree, Graphic Design, July 2011

Mon Valley Career and Technology Center, Charleroi, PA

Certificate of Merit, Multimedia Design, May 2008

SKILLS AND QUALIFICATIONS

- Understanding of mobile development with a focus on responsive web design and mobile first approach.
- Excellent understanding of designing user experiences and interfaces with a passion for usability and accessibility.
- Mastery of the Photoshop, Illustrator and Indesign as well as typography.
- Proficient with latest W3C standards, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Jr. Ruby on Rails skill sets working with Ruby 1.93 and Rails 3.
- Working experience using Foundation, Bootstrap and The Semantic Grid System.

RELATED EXPERIENCE

PPG Industries Pittsburgh, PA

Front End Web Developer

August 2012—Present

Develop websites using .Net in an MVC framework. Optimized all content using HTML5 and CSS3 with cross browser compliant code according to the latest W3C standards. Content planning and development for responsive web design.

Machovy Pittsburgh, PA

Front End Web Developer

August 2012—Present

Carried brand development and identity and promoted website traffic growth and marketing. Wire framed and developed content. Developed website using Ruby on Rails.

Kolano Design Pittsburgh, PA

Front End Web Developer / Graphic Designer

July 2011—July 2012

Designed marketing and advertising material including magazine ads, corporate identities and packages, billboards, annual reports and package design. Maintained multiple websites using wordpress. Customized themes according to company identity.

Pittsburgh Technical Institute,

Oakdale, PA

Visual Communications Assistant

March 2009—July 2011

Designed posters and signage for student activities. Redesigned and updated standard school displays. Organized image archive files, created certificates, produced event directories and photographed school events.

ACTIVITIES / ACHIEVEMENTS

Pittsburgh Technical Institute, Student Show First Place Award, May 2010 Pittsburgh Technical Institute, Portfolio Show Best of Show Award, July2011